<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anto Mathew on Anto Mathew - Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anto Mathew on Anto Mathew - Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anto-mathew.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Anto Mathew, a Senior Software Engineer with over 14 years of professional experience building high-impact web applications, scalable backend systems, and modern frontend architectures.
I work extensively with:
PHP (Symfony, Core PHP, CodeIgniter) React, Svelte, TypeScript Node.js RESTful APIs &amp;amp; Microservices Docker, Kubernetes, GitLab CI/CD WordPress, Magento Cloudflare, Redis, Varnish, Nginx What I Do Architect enterprise applications for 50,000+ global users Modernize legacy systems into modular, scalable architectures Build high-performance frontend apps using React &amp;amp; Svelte Implement CI/CD, automated deployments &amp;amp; Kubernetes clusters Create API-driven, cloud-ready applications Develop internal engineering tools to automate repetitive tasks Provide mentoring, architecture leadership &amp;amp; code quality guidance I’m passionate about AI in software development, automation, and building tools that improve developer productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/skills/</guid>
      <description>Core Skills Backend Development PHP 8+, Symfony 6/7 API Platform Laravel Node.js (CLI tools, automation) Frontend Development React.js Svelte TailwindCSS Vanilla JS, TypeScript DevOps &amp;amp; Cloud Docker Kubernetes GitLab CI/CD AWS EC2 Nginx reverse proxy Makefile automation CMS / Platforms WordPress Bedrock Sage Theme (Blade) Additional Skills Microservices JWT Authentication MySQL, MariaDB REST API Design System Architecture </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony Microservices Architecture</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/symfony-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/symfony-microservices/</guid>
      <description>Overview A complete microservices-based backend platform built with Symfony, using API Platform, DDD, CQRS, and JWT authentication.
Designed for high scalability, modularity, and real-world enterprise workflows.
Key Features Microservice separation: Auth, User, Employee, Department JWT-based authentication &amp;amp; role authorization Domain-driven folder structure Event-driven communication (RabbitMQ optional) Fully containerized using Docker API documentation auto-generated via Swagger / API Platform Database migrations using Doctrine Responsibilities Designed entire microservice architecture Implemented secure authentication service Built admin dashboard APIs for employee creation Implemented service-to-service communication Set up CI/CD pipeline for deployment Tech Stack Symfony 7, PHP 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Svelte  Application</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/svelte-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/svelte-application/</guid>
      <description>Overview A lightweight analytics dashboard built using Svelte, focusing on fast rendering and dynamic components.
Features Dynamic components with #each and conditional rendering Locale-based UI switching (tc, sc, en) Custom tooltip implementation without Bootstrap Component-level TypeScript validation API integration for charts and metrics Responsibilities Architecture of component structure Implemented reusable components with props Added locale switching logic Created tooltip system Worked with dynamic lists and API data Tech Stack Svelte, TypeScript, Fetch API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker &amp; Kubernetes Deployment – DevOps Setup</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/kubernetes-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/kubernetes-devops/</guid>
      <description>Overview A fully containerized DevOps environment used to deploy modern PHP + Node + React applications to AWS.
Features Single Docker image containing Nginx + PHP + MySQL (local dev) Kubernetes manifests for deployments &amp;amp; services GitLab CI/CD pipeline for automated deployment to EC2 Makefile for: Composer install Build Deploy Terraform optional for infrastructure provisioning Responsibilities Built Dockerfile with optimized layers Configured Kubernetes deployment &amp;amp; service YAML Added Nginx reverse proxy rules Created GitLab CI pipeline for build → push → deploy Deployed to AWS EC2 via kubectl Tech Stack Docker, Kubernetes, AWS EC2, GitLab CI/CD, Makefile, Nginx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Bedrock &#43; Sage Theme Website</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/wordpress-bedrock-sage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/wordpress-bedrock-sage/</guid>
      <description>Overview A full WordPress website built using the Bedrock structure and the Sage Blade-based theme to achieve a modern, modular, and secure development workflow.
Features Blade templating system Composer-managed WordPress REST API with custom fields Custom menu click tracking Advanced ACF + REST integration Clean MVC-like folder structure Responsibilities Extended REST API responses Built custom post types and fields Implemented frontend behaviour with JS tracking Integrated Sage templates with Blade Setup Bedrock environment for both local and production Tech Stack WordPress Bedrock, Sage, PHP, Composer, Blade, JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js CLI Tool for Content Migration</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/node-cli-migration-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/node-cli-migration-tool/</guid>
      <description>Overview A powerful Node.js-based CLI tool for automated content migration between legacy CMS systems.
Capabilities Folder traversal and file extraction JSON → TypeScript model auto-generation HTML cleanup and sanitization Bulk migration with progress tracking Error logging and retry functionality Responsibilities Designed CLI structure using Commander.js Implemented file system utilities Automated Blade/HTML cleanup functionality Added support for dynamic component generation Tech Stack Node.js, Commander.js, TypeScript, FS module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React-Based Investor Relations Website</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/react-ir-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/projects/react-ir-website/</guid>
      <description>Overview A modern React.js Investor Relations (IR) website for corporate financial reporting, regulatory disclosures, and investor communications.
Features Dynamic pages generated using JSON routing Reusable components for results, financial statements, filings API integrated for disclosures such as: Annual Reports Earnings Releases Press Announcements SEO-ready &amp;amp; mobile-optimized layout Light and fast UI using modern React hooks Responsibilities Architected the full UI component system Implemented routing using JSON-driven configuration Integrated with backend IR API Created reusable templates for financial widgets Tech Stack React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Senior Software Engineer - PHP</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/eqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/eqs/</guid>
      <description>Lead development of enterprise PHP/Symfony applications for 50,000+ users. Built React &amp;amp; Svelte applications using TypeScript with optimized performance. Architected REST APIs and microservices using Symfony API Platform. Reduced deployment time by 35% by implementing microservice architecture. Designed CI/CD pipelines (GitLab CI), reducing release time from 2 weeks to 3 days. Containerized systems using Docker ensuring 40% fewer environment issues. Implemented Kubernetes-based infrastructure achieving 99.7% uptime. Built automation tools using Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineer – PHP</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/sbl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/sbl/</guid>
      <description> Developed backend systems using PHP &amp;amp; CodeIgniter. Designed modular OOP-based components and reusable services. Improved page load time by 30% via caching &amp;amp; SQL optimization. Integrated REST APIs with frontend systems. Contributed to Agile development cycles (sprints, stand-ups, retrospectives). </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Project Manager &amp; Developer</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/unitybees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/unitybees/</guid>
      <description> Managed 10+ client projects end-to-end. Built custom CMS systems in Core PHP. Implemented Git workflows improving delivery pipeline by 50% fewer conflicts. Automated deployment &amp;amp; testing workflows improving timelines by 25%. Mentored development team &amp;amp; handled client communication. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP / Magento Developer</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/wub24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/wub24/</guid>
      <description> Built Magento modules &amp;amp; e-commerce features for global clients. Integrated payment gateways (PayPal, Stripe, Authorize.net). Improved catalog &amp;amp; DB performance by 40%. Implemented responsive UI &amp;amp; SEO improving conversions by 20%. Debugged and optimized high-traffic platforms processing 10,000+ monthly transactions. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Programmer (NIC Project)</title>
      <link>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/highcourt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anto-mathew.github.io/experience/highcourt/</guid>
      <description> Built internal judicial workflow automation systems. Developed case management, document tracking &amp;amp; reporting modules. Reduced manual workload by 60% using automation. Ensured security &amp;amp; compliance with government standards. Provided support, documentation &amp;amp; user training. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
